



THOMAS WHITING

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

LANGUAGES

PROFILE

Thomas is a dedicated Full Stack Developer who commits all of his time to make sure his work is up to the highest standard. In his prior working experience, Thomas gained experience working with complex IT systems and communicating directly with customers. At Integrify, Thomas takes the role of a team leader and contributes heavily to the community. The combination of his experiences and qualities make Thomas a valuable addition to any team.

RECENT PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio

CSS, HTML, Gatsby.js, TypeScript, Node.js

A single-page application to serve as a personal portfolio with project examples, contact form integration, and personal information. Most notably, the application would post contact form requests to an AWS API running a lambda function to handle mail directs.

Tico's Quest

CSS, HTML, React.js

A project with the aim to create a single-player game. The outcome is an HTML5 browser game that utilizes React.js.

SKILLS

Frontend: Accessibility, CSS, HTML, Gatsby.js, JavaScript, Next.js, React.js, Redux, SCSS, Type-

Backend: GraphQL, Node.js, Python, Rest API, TypeScript.

Database: MongoDB, PostgreSQL.

Testing: Jest.

DevOps / Cloud: AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Netlify. Others: Java for object-oriented programming.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Integrify | Helsinki, Finland | August 2020 - Present

- Serving as one of the team leaders.
- Taking numerous responsibilities in front-end development with JavaScript and TypeScript and applied frameworks and other tools such as React.js and Redux among many others.
- Contributing to the back-end development of various projects with Node.js and Express.js.
- · Building and managing databases with MongoDB and PostgreSQL.
- Conducting software tests with Jest.
- Collaborating with other developers of different seniority via GitHub Actions.

General Administrator

Shropshire Lettings | Shrewsbury, England, United Kingdom. | May 2019 - October 2019

- · Responsible for the website administration.
- · Responded to housing queries.
- · Updated and created marketing materials.
- · Archived legal documentation.

RMT Administrator

ReAssure UK | Telford, England, United Kingdom | May 2019 - October 2019

- Handled and archived legal documents.
- Directed general queries to appropriate teams.
- · Handled other sensitive documentation.

IT Technical Support

Social Telecoms CIC | Shrewsbury, England, United Kingdom | March 2014 - October 2014

- · Responsible for the repair and configuration of IT systems, hardware installation, and OS / Software installation.
- · Arranged monthly community engagement products and lessons.
- · Also, responsible for the IT equipment procurement.

EDUCATION

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp, distance learning

Udemy | Tampere, Finland | December 2019

Courses on Object-Oriented Programming with Java

University of Helsinki, Mooc.fi | Helsinki, Finland | June 2019